We all have a different approach to money – some of us like to spend it as soon as we have it, even splashing the cash on extravagant things, while some of us like to hold on to it and spend it carefully.
我们每个人对金钱都有不同的态度——有些人一有钱就想花掉，甚至会挥霍金钱买奢侈的东西，而有些人则喜欢把钱存起来，谨慎地花。
But for people who are very savvy about their cash, there are a number of interesting ways to invest it and, if things go well, make a tidy profit.
但是对于那些对金钱非常精明的人来说，有很多有趣的投资方式，如果一切顺利，还能赚一笔可观的利润。
Buying stamps, wine, coins and books are all different ways of investing your money.
购买邮票、葡萄酒、硬币和书籍都是不同的投资方式。
It comes with risks but can be thrilling as, hopefully, you watch the value of your investment rise.
虽然有风险，但当你，希望如此，看着投资价值上涨时，这可能会令人兴奋。
However, you need to know what you're doing and making your fortune is not guaranteed.
不过，你得清楚自己在做什么，而且发财也不是必然的。
If you're happy to take a gamble, then one of the most well-known ways of investing is by buying artwork.
如果你愿意冒险，那么最著名的投资方式之一就是购买艺术品。
By purchasing a painting and holding on to it, its value can increase by a handsome sum, but of course it's only when you sell it do you feel the financial benefit.
买下一幅画并持有它，其价值可能会大幅增加，但当然，只有当你卖掉它时才能获得经济收益。
Some people get quite lucky, particularly when they don't expect to make any money.
有些人非常幸运，尤其是在他们没指望赚钱的时候。
There are stories of people buying a painting in an antique shop for peanuts only to find out it's actually worth thousands of pounds.
有这样的故事：有人在古董店以极低的价格买了一幅画，结果发现它实际上价值数千英镑。
Investing in art appears to be a hobby for the rich, but not always.
投资艺术似乎是富人的爱好，但并非总是如此。
Recently, an investor's dream came true when a picture believed to have been painted by Leonardo da Vinci sold for £341m.
最近，一位投资者的梦想成真了，一幅据信是列奥纳多・达・芬奇（Leonardo da Vinci）创作的画作以3.41亿英镑的价格售出。
He had bought it about 60 years ago in an auction for just £45 thinking it was only painted by a follower of da Vinci.
大约60年前，他在一次拍卖中以45英镑的价格买下了这幅画，当时他以为这幅画只是达・芬奇的一位仿效者的作品。
Of course this is a rare story and investing in artwork is not a guarantee to make you a millionaire.
当然，这是一个罕见的故事，投资艺术品并不能保证你成为百万富翁。
Patrick Connolly, a financial adviser at Chase de Vere, told BBC News that to invest in art as a true investment, "you need a starting fund of at least £5,000, and possibly up to £500,000, which can be used to buy individual works of art or invested in an art fund."
大通德维尔（Chase de Vere）的财务顾问帕特里克・康诺利（Patrick Connolly）告诉BBC新闻，要将艺术作为真正的投资，“你需要至少5000英镑的启动资金，可能高达50万英镑，这些资金可以用来购买单件艺术品，也可以投资于艺术基金。”
He feels investing in art is too risky and recommends their clients not to invest in it because the downsides outweigh the upsides.
他认为投资艺术风险太大，并建议客户不要投资，因为缺点大于优点。
But if you're still keen, there are art fairs, such as The Affordable Art Fair, and websites aimed at buyers with a modest budget.
但是如果你仍然感兴趣，有一些艺术博览会，比如“平价艺术博览会”（The Affordable Art Fair），还有针对预算有限的买家的网站。
Patrick Connolly says the best approach here is to buy something you like and can afford and "if it goes up in value, that should be just an added bonus."
帕特里克・康诺利说，这里最好的方法是买你喜欢且买得起的东西，“如果它升值了，那应该只是一个额外的好处。”
If this has spoilt your plans for your investment portfolio, maybe there's more chance of winning big money by buying a lottery ticket!
如果这破坏了你投资组合的计划，也许买彩票更有可能赚大钱！